CIAN ROBERTS

Australian Citizen

Summary

I am currently in my 5th and final year of studies at UTS with industry experience in full stack application development.

I like solving interesting problems and working collaboratively.

I take pride in my ability to rapidly learn new technologies and adapt to any challenge.

Highlights

- Strong skills in writing programs to solve problems with unique approaches.
- Experience in writing algorithms, scripting, API development and UI/UX design.
- Exposure to a wide range of programming languages and technologies.
- Some exposure to Al.

Professional Experience

February 2024 to August 2024

IOT Automation

Full-Stack Junior Web Developer

IOT Automation produces smart, modular lighting systems for use in underground mines and tunnels.

As a junior full-stack engineer I was tasked with creating new features as well as optimising performance of the web-app. In my position I:

- Worked on a major feature project, collaborating with other key engineers.
- Researched and implemented efficient react-redux architecture and methodologies to vastly improve frontend performance through smart data management.
- Worked closely with firmware testing by manipulating binary/ASCII characters in python.

July 2021 to January 2022

Skodel

Full-Stack Junior Web Developer

Skodel provides an online platform for organizations to better understand the mental wellbeing of their team.

I worked in a small team working on new features and updates for the web app. In my position I:

- Developed UI for both desktop and mobile application views, working on building a clean user experience with collapsible views and better-organized navigation.
- Built password reset functionality through emails and limited time access codes.
- Worked with GraphQL to guery and manipulate database entries.
- Built and maintained unit tests with CircleCl.

Other Experience

December 2019 - January 2024 JB Hi-Fi

Operations team member.

Working with across different departments to manage stock. Managing online orders.

Education

ATAR of 90.65

Graduated 2019 **HSC**St. Pius X College, Chatwood

2020 – 2024 University of Technology, Sydney Batchelor of Engineering (Software) Diploma of Professional Practice

Extra-Curricular / Personal Projects

- Created a playable chess game using python. Added functional UI using the PyGame library allowing for click-and-drag gameplay with two players on one machine.
- Participated in debating throughout college years.
- Coached junior tennis students at local club over college breaks (intermittent, 2017-2018).

Other Accomplishments

- Received certificate for the 2024 OpenD/I Data Verification Hackathon hosted by Openmesh. I was one of 20 people from an initial 200 to be in a final screening group for a potential hire.
- Captain of Debating in final year of college. I worked in coaching with junior and senior debaters, as well as assisting with the organisation of over 50 students on our hosting nights.
- Academic Excellence award for ranking 1st within the college in the subject of Information Processes and Technology, and ranking 2nd within the college in the subject of Software Design and Development.

Tools / Technologies

- Python, C, C++, C#, Golang, JavaScript, Java, HTML5, CSS3, SQL
- Programming paradigms, Object-oriented programming, Software development cycles.
- Applications
 - VS Code, JetBrains Products, BlueJ, Photoshop, Microsoft Office Products, Windows OS, Linux OS.
- Programming frameworks
 - o React.js, GraphQL, React-Redux
- Exposure to simple AI classification models
 - I have worked on building, training, and comparing different AI data classification models to accurately predict an airline company based on the data from a given flight.
 I have also developed a multilayer perceptron classification model with binary output.

Results (as of 26/8/2024):

GPA - 5.93 WAM - 78.44

2023		
Computer Graphics	83	D
Introduction to Computer Game Development	79	D
Real-Time Operating Systems	78	D
Engineering Project Management	78	D
Machine Learning	75	D
Engineering Research Preparation	70	С
Entrepreneurship and Commercialisation	65	С
Professional Practise Preparation 2	PASS	N/A
2022		
Economics and Finance for Engineering Projects	93	HD
Software Architecture	91	HD
Secure Programming and Penetration Testing	87	HD
Software Analysis Studio	87	HD
Software Development Studio	83	D
Design and Innovation Fundamentals	80	D
Introduction to Data Analytics	68	С
Professional Practise Review	PASS	N/A
2021		
Physical Modelling	86	HD
Software Engineering Studio 1A	81	D
Information System Development Methodologies	80	D
Work Integrated Learning 1	PASS	N/A
Engineering Professional Experience	PASS	N/A
Engineering Practice Preparation 1	PASS	N/A
2020		
Engineering Communication	79	D
Systems Testing and Quality Management	77	D
Database Fundamentals	77	D
Applications Programming	74	С
Mathematical Modelling 2	73	С
Programming Fundamentals	71	С
Business Requirements Modelling	70	С
Mathematical Modelling 1	59	Р